<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Katarzyna (Kasia) Kobalczyk</title>
    <link>https://example.com/publications/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Katarzyna (Kasia) Kobalczyk</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu657cd6d5c75f57c23416a235dc5083f6_34177_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Katarzyna (Kasia) Kobalczyk</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publications/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tabular Few-Shot Generalization Across Heterogenous Feature Spaces</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publications/articles/flat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publications/articles/flat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;imgage&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /publications/articles/flat/FLAT_diagram_hu70fa20c8d5553d07968fe95a2b5925cb_425601_0869fd281d26d942a501803941531fdb.webp 400w,
               /publications/articles/flat/FLAT_diagram_hu70fa20c8d5553d07968fe95a2b5925cb_425601_4c12e7814fa1c824226c48060df617ca.webp 760w,
               /publications/articles/flat/FLAT_diagram_hu70fa20c8d5553d07968fe95a2b5925cb_425601_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/publications/articles/flat/FLAT_diagram_hu70fa20c8d5553d07968fe95a2b5925cb_425601_0869fd281d26d942a501803941531fdb.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;353&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

Despite the prevalence of tabular datasets, learning with just a few labelled examples remains an under-explored area of research. Existing few-shot learning methods are not directly applicable to tabular datasets due to the variation in the relationships between the columns, their underlying meanings, and their permutational invariance. To address these challenges, we propose FLAT—the first solution for the generalized problem of tabular few-shot learning, including the critical aspect of knowledge sharing between datasets with heterogenous sets of columns. Using a Dataset2Vec-inspired encoder, FLAT learns a low-dimensional embedding space of tabular datasets and their individual columns that captures the key characteristics of datasets; this enables knowledge transfer and generalization to previously unseen datasets. Based on the embedding of a new dataset, a decoder network generates the parameters of the predictive target network. To handle the varying number of features, their permutational invariance and structural relationship, we implement the target network as a Graph Attention Network. Using a collection of datasets from the UCI Machine Learning Repository, we demonstrate successful generalization to different tabular datasets and a considerable improvement over existing baselines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cegpy: Modelling with chain event graphs in Python</title>
      <link>https://example.com/publications/articles/cegpy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/publications/articles/cegpy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;imgage&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /publications/articles/cegpy/cegpy_hua68a355d8bc9858a5831efd1c8071401_299686_94e1fa56beb24ddc504a833145ccabc6.webp 400w,
               /publications/articles/cegpy/cegpy_hua68a355d8bc9858a5831efd1c8071401_299686_fd7d8effde1650fd6ecdad109691f606.webp 760w,
               /publications/articles/cegpy/cegpy_hua68a355d8bc9858a5831efd1c8071401_299686_1200x1200_fit_q100_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://example.com/publications/articles/cegpy/cegpy_hua68a355d8bc9858a5831efd1c8071401_299686_94e1fa56beb24ddc504a833145ccabc6.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;383&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chain event graphs (CEGs) are a recent family of probabilistic graphical models that generalise the popular Bayesian networks (BNs) family. Crucially, unlike BNs, a CEG is able to embed, within its graph and its statistical model, asymmetries exhibited by a process. These asymmetries might be in the conditional independence relationships or in the structure of the graph and its underlying event space. Structural asymmetries are common in many domains, and can occur naturally (e.g. a defendant vs prosecutor’s version of events) or by design (e.g. a public health intervention). Whilst two CEG packages exist in R for modelling processes with asymmetric conditional independencies, there currently exists no software that allows a user to leverage the theoretical developments of the CEG model family in modelling processes with structural asymmetries. In this paper, we present cegpy—the first Python implementation of CEGs and the first across all languages to support structurally asymmetric processes. cegpy contains an implementation of Bayesian learning and probability propagation algorithms for CEGs. We illustrate the functionality of cegpy using a structurally asymmetric dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
